MEHUL JOSHI

- m1vjoshi@gmail.com
- h (425) 943-1672
- a 19311 25th AVE SE, Bothell, Washington 98012

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a self-directed and motivated student developer with experience working effectively in dynamic environments. I am fluent in Java, Python, and Javascript programming languages. I have an innate ability to design and create software that helps people in a myriad of ways.

SKILLS

- · Application design
- · Creative self-starter
- · Originality
- · Fast learner
- · Sales expertise

EDUCATION

North Creek High School Bothell, WA • 2019

High School Diploma

University of Washington Seattle, WA • 2023 Bachelor of Science

CERTIFICATIONS

Responsive Web Design (FreeCodeCamp.org): Given to those individuals who finish 6 programming projects in HTML and CSS to make responsive websites. Approximate time of completion: 300 hours

JavaScript Data Structures and Algorithms (FreeCodeCamp.org): Given to those individuals who master over 300+ hours of Javascript work. Approximate time of completion: 300 hours.

WORK HISTORY

Interactive Math Academy - Python And Math Tutor Bellevue, Washington • 06/2019 - Current

- Explained math concepts in caring and encouraging environment to help kids thrive and learn.
- Helped grow the understanding of python for middle schoolers in a effective way.

Self-Employeed - Freelance Computer Science Tutor

Bothell, Washington • 09/2016 - Current

I taught and basic Java to my fellow peers that were taking AP CS A. For this role I did all of my own advertising, planning, and marketing.

Self-Employeed - Lead Designer For Wooden Box Company Bothell, Washington • 06/2016 - 09/2018

 Worked with industry standards to make a better solution for expensive wooden raised planter beds.

Self-Employeed - Paver Designer And Installer Bothell, Washington • 05/2016 - 07/2018

- Utilized knowledge of carpentry and general construction to complete attractive finish work.
- Operated tools, equipment and machinery according to safety standards.
- · Worked with all types of weather and ground conditions.
- · Calculated materials and time needed for each job.

PROJECTS

- Dofleini Chess (https://github.com/csmjoshi/Chess): An intuitive way to play chess in today's chaotic world. Play with a friend, foe, or computer for fun.
- · Digit Recognizer (private repository):

This was one of my first projects in Computer Vision. It takes tons of hand written digit data and with a neural network it predicts which digit is the given digit.

Cancer prediction model (private repository):
Implemented a neural network that takes in the size of a tumor, shape of a tumor along with many other factors and predicts if it is cancerous or not.

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

 AP Computer Science A, AP Physics 1, AP Physics 2, AP Literature, AP Calculus AB, AP Biology, AP Government, AP Language and Composition, CHS Physiology, CHS Neurobiology